After that,
in order to save Mayuri,
I time leaped repeatedly.
But...
no matter what I did,
Mayuri...
...died.
Even if Moeka and SERN never attacked,
it was like fate itself kept murdering her.
It was like the entire world
was conspiring to kill her.
The cars aren't moving!
The train's stopped.
Hurry!
Take a back road or something!
That's not really an option, sir.
Huh? Mayushii's watch isn't working.
That's strange.
I just wound it.
Again...
Again!
Mayuri!
Shiina Mayuri was the one who died.
Okabe...
I mean, Okabe Rintaro has escaped.
No matter what I do,
no matter what I try,
she dies.
It's like fate...
I see. So this is...
There's nothing like that!
The Organization... Steins Gate...
and fate!
They don't exist!
Even the billions of heartbeats in the world
suujuuoku mo no kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
are nothing to you but insignificant
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
Whether we’re trapped in the past or lamenting over the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
predetermination does not allow even the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
are but vain privileges allowed to us
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what both clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
So now I cross worldlines every second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no loop e to
And so, a time loop without sadness will once again
nomikomareteyuku kodoku no kansokusha
engulf me, the lone observer
Physically
Necrosis
What do you mean?
Explain!
I just got to the individual character route.
At least let me save—
I'll do it.
Just get out of Akihabara.
Got it?
Okabe...
Mayuri just left.
It's exactly the same.
No matter how many times I try to save her,
in the end...
Assistant
Did something happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Even the message is the same.
Everything.
"Shining Finger."
"I have new information regarding the time machine."
"I'd like to talk to you alone."
Don't move.
Put your hands up.
Who are you people?!
Part-time job.
Arc rewrite.
I know you're planning to attack the lab and kidnap us!
How?
Because I've come from the future!
Do you understand?
Now answer me!
My phone...
No!
Answer me now!
Are you with SERN?
Rounder.
Rounder?
Our mission is to recover the IBN 5100.
You're the one who stole it!
I don't know anything.
Don't fuck with me!
You sent that D-Mail...
I see.
The worldline changed,
so she has no memory of sending that message.
Why do you plan to attack the lab?
The IBN 5100 isn't there anymore.
Too late.
Answer me!
Three reasons.
First:
You've learned something you shouldn't have.
Second:
You made a time machine.
Third:
You wanted to publicly announce it.
You knew all that?
Does SERN know?
My orders come from FB.
FB?
Is that an organization within SERN?
FB is everything to me.
Where am I?
Don't move.
Are you John Titor?
You're the only person he could be.
No!
Where am I?
The bomb threat has halted all the trains.
According to plan.
Capture Makise Kurisu and Hashida Itaru.
No one else is needed.
Wait!
W-Wait!
Please don't kill Mayuri!
I'm sorry!
I was wrong!
I never wanted to expose SERN!
I'll give you the time leap machine!
I'll never tell anyone what I learned!
Begin the mission.
Please! I'll do anything!
Please... It was just simple curiosity...
It was a game!
So... just spare Mayuri...
It's too late.
Mayuri...
Mayuri!
Shut up!
Mayuri...
What's wrong?
Were you napping?
This again...
I can't take this anymore!
Okabe!
What's wrong?
You don't need to destroy it.
We decided we aren't doing the time leap.
What's gotten into you?
You're going shopping for the party, right?
The party...
Wait, Okabe!
It's the bullet train!
No, the bullet train is white.
Oka—Kyouma...
Where's Mayuri?
Mayuri already left.
I know.
I know she came to invite you to the party...
and that she's going to meet her friend who cosplays...
I know she's looking forward to the party.
All of it!
I'm sorry.
But I...
What are you doing over there?
Kurisu...
That's the first time you've ever called me by my real name.
What happened?
No, what's going to happen?
You time leaped, didn't you?
It's all...
my fault.
Okabe.
It's all my fault.
I never should've told Daru to hack into SERN.
I never should've said to make the time machine.
I never should've invited Moeka to be a lab mem!
It's my fault... and Mayuri...
You're pushing yourself too hard, idiot.
We don't know if the time leap machine is completely safe.
It's possible you could completely erase yourself from existence.
On a fundamental level, humans are temporal creatures.
Heidegger... I was just about to say that.
I learned that phrase from you.
That's kind of creepy.
It's like you're peeking inside my head,
but I guess that's what a time leap is.
What should I do?
When will the lab be attacked?
After 7:30.
I can think of several possible causes for Mayuri's death,
but we don't have time to talk.
Let's go.
Mayuri's a dear friend.
I want to save her too!
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
I want to help you.
I really do.
Hey, mad scientist!
You're going to change the world, right?
Of course!
Right?
I set the time to five or so hours ago,
right when the time leap machine was created.
If you go back before it's completed, it's possible I won't finish it.
So you go back in time,
and once the time leap machine is done,
send everyone away and tell me what we just discussed.
If you say you've come from the future,
I'll probably believe you.
How can you be sure?
I know myself better than anyone.
I'm the one who made the time leap machine
to begin with.
You mean you're confident about your work?
I guess so.
When I saw you back there, I was certain.
Certain that you had time leaped, I mean.
Just in case, let's decide on a keyword.
Right now, what I want most is
My Fork.
You want one?
A fork?
Yeah, I already have My Spoon.
Don't be so nosy!
Here we go!
Okay.
Five hours ago,
I won't remember that you called me Kurisu...
Do you think you could hold this?
Like this?
That's right.
Keep it spread out like that!
That ribbon's cute.
Isn't it?
Want to try it on?
I still have some cosplay outfits for ComiMa.
Cosplay, huh?
Interested?
N-No way!
I couldn't wear that in public...
I see.
Five hours ago, Mayuri hadn't left.
As I recall, her cosplay outfit and the time leap machine were completed at the same time.
It's done!
I win!
We were racing.
I lose.
But we're almost done too.
Now it's finished.
This is...
We won't do the experiment!
Damn... Was that too sudden?
What do you mean?
Y-You're all tired.
We'll talk later.
We're done for today.
I'll take a plate.
One plate.
What are you doing here?
I already ordered when I got your message.
I didn't think you were a regular here.
I-I'm not a regular!
Mayuri told me about this place.
So what did you want to talk about?
You told us all to leave, and then
you suddenly texted me.
You see...
I've come from five hours in the future.
What? That's the stupidest line I've ever heard.
H-Hey! That isn't what you said!
You said you'd probably believe me!
What are you talking about?
Probably believe you?
I wouldn't say anything that illogical.
You did say it!
"I'm the one who made the time leap machine to begin with."
You looked really proud too!
Are you a moron?
Whatever...
I really want to smack her...
Right now, what you want most is...
"My Fork."
Well?
I really told you that?
The five-hours-from-now me?
You said you already had "My Spoon."
Screw you, future me...
You believe me now, right?
Yeah... So the machine works like I thought it would.
It's perfect.
Here's your plate.
I see.
That sounds bad, if it's all true.
Yeah.
Rather than help Mayuri escape, have you tried stopping Moeka...
A Rounder, you called her?
How about stopping her and her group?
I did.
But I couldn't stop Mayuri's death.
I see.
For something to occur, it must have a cause.
Cause
Death
Effect
Normally, death would be preceded
by some proximate phenomenon
like an accident or an illness,
but we can't be sure about the cause.
The Rounders are the proximate cause of Mayuri's death,
but the real cause is likely different.
So even if the Rounders never appear,
Mayuri still dies.
Cause
Death
Effect
Then what's the cause?
I don't know.
It's possible that the cause of Mayuri's death
is Mayuri's own birth.
You mean her life just expires?
That's fatalism!
Indeed.
So I won't suggest it.
The cause should be something
that initiated this series of events.
Initiated...
Is it possible that if this wasn't completed, Mayuri would...
Wait.
It's dangerous to jump to conclusions!
But...
Makise Kurisu is right.
You're...
Do you know something?
You're more or less correct.
Fixing everything won't be as easy
as not completing the time leap machine.
To save the world,
you need to reach a Beta worldline.
You must cross the 1% divergence barrier.
The divergence number
indicates this worldline's location.
And the only clue we have as to what it is
is this divergence meter.
Nixie tubes?
Whoever made it has good taste.
Of course he does.
You're the one who made it.
I did?
You have the power to retain
your memories when moving worldlines.
In the future, you made this meter
to numerically display
the difference between this worldline and the previous one you came from.
0.337187...
That's this worldline.
A worldline is like a woven braid or this rope.
This rope looks like it's a single line,
but actually, it's comprised of many thin threads.
The threads are the worldlines.
One never touches the others,
but they all go to the same place.
In other words,
they all move toward a world in which Mayuri dies?
But if the worldline drastically changes
from this Alpha worldline to a Beta worldline
and over the 1% barrier,
another outcome would occur.
You guys use that one.
Wait.
I can't climb up with just that.
Oh, fine...
Just wait here.
Who is Amane, anyway?
She's definitely a professional...
of some kind.
Let's go.
Hurry.
The Alpha and Beta worldlines
are worldlines with completely different results.
Normally, it's impossible to move between them.
Even if you change the past
using time leaps and D-Mails,
you can't do it.
But sometimes, major convergent events occur,
and the choices made then split the world into multiple worldlines.
In recent history, it would be 1991 when the Gulf War occurred.
2000, with Y2K,
and 2010 with the creation of the first time machine.
This is...
When the split occurs,
it's possible to move from the Alpha worldlines to the Beta.
How is it done?
How—
Wait!
Before that,
tell us who you are.
This is...
a time machine.
I'm from the year 2036.
Suzuha...
I am the time traveler...
John Titor.
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
With my field of view restricted
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
I cannot escape the merciless control of the twelve
ansoku no asu wo negatta
While wishing for a tomorrow of repose
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
I headed for the sacred event horizon in my hand
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
Pledges are imprisoned, and false evidences are showing their outline
seimei no tenchi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
This world of life blindly lets the time pass by
habatake butterfly
Spread your wings
kiseki no butterfly
butterfly of miracles
anata he sasagu
I dedicate it to you
namida no butterfly
Oh butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
butterfly of radiance
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
everything will now be rewritten