World War III.
By 2036,
it will have resulted in 5.7 billion casualties worldwide.
And this is what starts it.
Huh? What is it?
It's some kind of robot?
Does it transform and stuff?
A time machine.
Seriously?
I knew you'd recognize it, Uncle.
Then that makes this easy.
Come with me.
I refuse.
Okarin?
I came here from the Alpha worldline.
Over the past three weeks,
I jumped worldlines again and again,
sacrificing Kurisu in order to return to the Beta worldline.
I won't let it all be for naught!
Kurisu?
Wasn't that the name of the scientist
who was stabbed at the Radio Kaikan?
Okabe Rintaro,
what if I told you that the way to avoid World War III
is, on July 28th, 2010,
to prevent Makise Kurisu's death?
What do you mean?
I don't know the details,
but I have one mission:
To save Makise Kurisu
and to go to the one worldline
unaffected by the attractor field,
the Steins Gate!
Claims of life and meaningless proofs
inochi no shuchou to muimi no shoumei
anata ni wa taikutsu shinogi ni taranu koukei
are not enough to amuse you
shihaisha kidori no orokana shuzoku wa
Acting as the leader of a foolish group
unuboreta chisetsuna teiri wo narabeta
you lay down childish theories
mugen to shinjita ai mo sora no kanata mo
Infinite love and the distant sky
bokutachi ni shimesareta kasou no jiyuu
are but virtual liberties shown to us
yuugen sore wa mujihi ni toki wo kizami
Finitude is the merciless passage of time
asu sae mo hitei suru sentaku e
as I head towards my choice to deny even tomorrow
Hacking to the Gate
ikutsu mo no kagayakeru hibi nakama to no yakusoku
I must never break the promise to my friends
nakatta koto ni wa shite wa ikenai
of the shining days we would be together
sono tame ni toki wo azamuku nokosareta shikake ni
For that is why I deceive time with the tricks I am left with
mou mayoi wa nai kodoku no kansokusha
I no longer have any hesitations, the lone observer
Open the
Steins Gate
Steins Gate?
The architects of this plan were
my father and your future self.
None of it is more than a hypothesis.
It's possible for the theory to be wrong,
for there to be no Steins Gate worldline,
but I'm going regardless.
I'll bet on the chance that a shining future's waiting for me.
If you're coming with me,
then take my hand.
Um,
Mayushii didn't really understand any of that,
but if this person,
this Kurisu, is important to you,
shouldn't you try to help her?
World War III sounds like one of your crazy delusions.
No one else could handle it.
I don't care about the 5.7 billion people in the future...
but...
Thank you.
Let's go.
Two people can get in it?
Of course!
This is my dad's masterpiece.
Okarin!
Leave your phone.
It might interfere with your phone in the past.
I'll be back.
Good luck.
This is a time machine.
Yeah,
I stopped in 1975 and 2000.
It's working fine,
but it's running out of fuel.
Wait. It can go from past to future?
Of course it can.
It's a time machine.
I see.
Is that because we're in a different worldline now?
Sit down.
We'll head to just before noon on July 28th.
We can't change location,
so if we arrive too early, it'll spread panic at the Radio Kaikan,
possibly affecting Makise Kurisu's actions.
Your first time, the Gs are pretty tough.
Get ready.
Okarin...
What is this?
These always show up.
I guess they're like fragments of time.
Pretty, huh?
Let's go!
W-Wait.
I think I'm going to throw up.
What a wimp.
Hurry!
Don't let your other self see you.
It'll cause a serious time paradox.
How long until the stabbing?
Twenty minutes or so, I guess.
I'll prepare the time machine.
You protect her, Uncle.
Stop calling me that.
July 28th.
On the day I saw Kurisu lying in a pool of blood,
I came with Mayuri to see
Doctor Nakabachi's press conference.
I heard a noise on the roof.
That's right. After that, Mayuri went to the seventh-floor Upa machines.
Oh, no!
You called me here for this?
There aren't many left of this series, and Mayushii's...
Oh well.
I'll take the back stairs to the eighth floor.
It's a metal... a metal Upa!
Is it rare?
Extremely!
Now that I'm here...
I'm sorry.
K-Kurisu?
H-How do you know my name?
Kurisu is alive.
Have we met somewhere?
Kurisu...
Are you listening—
What's wrong?
Answer me.
I...
I'm... trying...
Wait!
Wait a second!
In the handouts, you can read about the time machine's basic design.
Doctor Nakabachi's Time Machine Invention Press Conference
I will use this conference as an opportunity to discuss the fundamental theory behind it.
Doctor Nakabachi
The operation notes said that you'd be able to identify Makise Kurisu.
Can you?
Yeah.
Also, it's dangerous to take her outside.
If we don't figure out who stabbed her,
we can't change her fate.
Just like Mayuri?
Doctor!
What is it?
You know exactly what!
What is this "time machine theory" of yours?
Kerr Black Holes?
worldlines?
You stole all of this from John Titor!
Kurisu will be stabbed right here soon.
Is she really going to be here?
Wait! Maybe she was stabbed elsewhere and brought here.
Yeah... That's possible!
Kurisu?
So it does happen here.
What's she reading?
A time machine?
Is that why she's the key to changing worldlines?
What do you want?
Daddy, I wanted you to read this.
Daddy?
Doctor Nakabachi?
You contacted me for the first time in seven years.
You asked me to come to your press conference, right?
That was my inspiration.
Wait. So Kurisu's dad is...
So I thought I could use it to theorize a time machine.
I wanted to hear your ideas.
If this is accepted, you can use it
as revenge for everyone who kicked you out—
I wasn't kicked out!
I got sick of them and left.
Sorry.
It's not bad.
Really?
If you're okay with it,
I thought we could put both of our names on the paper
because you inspired me—
Don't be stupid.
Leave!
I'll publish this paper under my name.
Wait!
You wouldn't steal it, right, Daddy?
I never thought you'd resort to tha—
Shut up!
How dare you call it stealing?!
Why are you so smart?
A girl shouldn't be smarter than her father!
If it weren't for you, I would've been considered smart!
If it weren't for you...
You're that kid from earlier.
So that's it?
You were plotting to ruin my conference together, huh?
I see.
So that's it.
Daddy!
I'll protect her!
How dare you insult me?
Why, you...
Stop it, Daddy!
Please!
Don't even speak to me!
Oh, shit!
What do you know?
You don't know how I feel.
You don't know how I've been humiliated
and the hell I've been through!
If it weren't for you...
Don't...
Don't do it!
Kurisu...
K-Kurisu!
Fools.
This is the perfect end for you.
I'm sorry for getting you involved.
Why?
Because he's my dad,
I wanted him to accept me.
That's all.
Kurisu...
I'm scared...
I... I don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
I don't...
Kurisu...
Kurisu!
They're back already!
Okarin!
Okarin, that blood...
It's all right.
It isn't his.
I was the one who killed Kurisu.
Okarin?
I know it hurts, but you can't give up yet.
We have enough fuel to go back one more time.
Shut up!
Nothing will change!
The attractor field convergence will kill her all over again.
It's your phone.
A message?
Open it.
But...
Just do it.
Turn on the TV.
Turn on the TV?
The TV?
Doctor Nakabachi
Defects to Russia
Mysterious Fire in Cargo Bay
The plane carrying Doctor Nakabachi made it to Russia,
despite a mysterious cargo bay fire.
We were very fortunate.
If this hadn't triggered the metal detector,
the paper would've burnt up.
Ma
yu
shii
Huh?
That's Mayushii's metal Upa!
Look. It has Mayushii's name on it!
She's right.
But what's it doing in Russia?
That paper is the start of everything.
Next comes the international time machine arms race.
If you control time, you control the world.
And that causes a world war.
5.7 billion lives are at stake.
Save Makise Kurisu and change this worldline!
It's impossible.
It's just like with Mayuri.
No matter what I do, it'll end up the same.
Kurisu will die.
How can you say that after only one time?
One time?!
It's more than that.
How many times...
How many times do you think I've failed?!
I already know
how insane this time loop is
and what an unforgiving fate it has in store.
I knew this...
I knew this would happen.
I'm tired.
I'm so tired.
You're not the kind of person to quit halfway.
Mayushii knows this!
You're not the kind of person to ever give up.
Even when Mayushii couldn't say goodbye to her grandmother,
you never stopped going to her grave.
That's why I could say goodbye.
That's why I got better!
So don't give up.
You should've received a video file on July 28th.
July 28th...
You should be able to watch it
now that you've failed to rescue Makise Kurisu once.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry I lied to you.
The plan required you to fail once,
so that you could see this.
What is this?
Nice to meet myself, I suppose. Myself 15 years ago.
It's Okarin!
If you've opened this video mail,
then you've failed to rescue Kurisu.
It hurts, doesn't it?
But that pain spawned my relentless obsession,
so it was a necessary step.
You could say it was a build-up.
Now we can begin the true plan,
the plan to save Makise Kurisu
and enter Steins Gate.
We have two objectives.
First, we must destroy the time machine thesis,
taken by Doctor Nakabachi to Russia.
And second, we must save the life of Makise Kurisu.
If I could do that...
But avoiding her death and changing the past is an impossibility
due to the attractor field convergence.
Isn't that right?
I'll do my best to explain.
Saving Makise Kurisu is very much possible.
You're just approaching it incorrectly.
Listen well.
You must not change the established past.
You must not undo what you witnessed on that day.
If you do either, the past will be rewritten, and all will be lost.
Remember your experiences in the Alpha worldline.
It was only three weeks,
but you should have memories of your time with Makise Kurisu,
of everything that was sacrificed to rescue Mayuri,
and everything that happened.
You must not let those three weeks go to waste.
You must not undo them.
The only reason you wish so desperately to save her
is because of the worldlines you experienced.
And it is for that reason
I devoted my life to developing a time machine.
The reason you've managed to get
as far as you have is that we both want to save Kurisu.
Thus, you must deceive your other self.
Save her without changing the past where she died.
Make your past self
mistake a living Kurisu for a dead one.
If you do, the past won't change.
I get it.
What does he mean?
Okarin, do you know?
I know you'll understand me.
Oh, one more thing... The time machine ID is C204.
I'm sure you know what that stands for.
Christina...
And I'm the one who named the target worldline Steins Gate.
I'm sure you know why I named it that.
It doesn't really mean anything.
Isn't that right?
I will now explain the parameters
of the final mission: Operation Skuld.
Modify the result without changing the established past.
The past consists of Makise Kurisu lying in a pool of blood,
kako wa hanareteyuki mirai wa chikazukuno?
The past retreats, but does the future truly approach?
and Okabe Rintaro seeing her there.
Change the past without changing that.
kansokusha wa itsuka mujun ni kizuku
An observer would realize the contradictions there
Deceive your past self.
Deceive the world.
kami no tsukuridashita sekai wa kanzennaru mono de zettai no kinkou
This world shaped by God is perfect and lies in absolute balance
Those are the necessary steps to reach Steins Gate.
Good luck.
El Psy Kongroo.
sore wa orikasanaru guuzen uchuu kibo no kiseki
A superimposed coincidence, a miracle on a cosmic scale
What was that?
Was that you, 15 years from now?
mamoraretekita GATE "kisei" wa owatta
The restrictions on the guarded gate are now abolished
He had a pretty deep voice!
Open the Eyes
"zero" ga kako de "ichi" ga mirai "ima" wa dokonimo nai
"Zero" is the past and "One" is the future, "The Present" is a fabrication
somuku koto no dekinu LOGIC
This is an undeniable logic
Operation Skuld?
El Psy Kongroo?
Open the Eyes
I still talk like that when I'm 33 years old?
heikousuru musuu no sen sentaku wa boutoku e
Amidst the countless parallel lines, I choose blasphemy
I sound like a such a childish fool!
bokura no "sonzai" sae utagau sono me ni utsuru keshiki wa
Doubting existence itself, Those Eyes bear witness to
Okarin?
I'll do it,
if that is choice of Steins Gate.
"shuusoku" o suru
Convergence
I am the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma!
Deceiving the world is nothing to me!
He's back to the usual Okarin.
Still, Mayushii likes Okarin better when he's like this.
futatsu no hari ga sasu jikan no gainen mo
Even the basic concept of time, as depicted by two hands of a clock
I'll say it once more.
kansokusha shidai de hizumi o miseru
Will bend and distort to the choice of the Observer
I am...
the mad scientist...
kami ni ataerareta eichi wa kanarazu "hate" ga aru zettai no ryouiki
The knowledge God gifted us must have some limit, an absolute territory
Hououin Kyouma...
and this world is in the palm of my hand!
Sore wa oroka yue no guuzen manekarezaru kiseki
It tells us that these are foolish notions and unwanted miracles
Tozasaretekita gate "kisei" wa owatta
The gate that once was shut is supervised no more
Open the eyes
Kousoku he to te wo nobashita omoide no parusu ga
My mind wished to reach the speed of light
Tobikomu fukashigi na logic
and fell into an unfathomable logic
Open the eyes
Uchuu ga mada kakushimotta chitsujo no nai riron
The lawless rules of the universe remain hidden from us
Mugen to yobareta ten to ten ga fusei na chikara wo karite
What we call eternity is but dots connected, empowering each other
"Saisei" wo suru
and resurrecting us time and time again